谁是小不点儿
Who the winny-binny boy?
你是个小小的小不点儿
You the winny-winny-binny-binny boy!
别哭呀
Don't cry.
他为什么还在哭
Why is he still crying?
让我来抱他一会儿
Let me hold him for a sec.
来 爸爸抱
Here we go.
不哭了
There we are.
或许是我的问题
Maybe it's me.
别傻了 小本喜欢你
Don't be silly. Ben loves you.
他只是一个牢骚小先生
He's just being Mr. Cranky Pants.
我曾经和一位牢骚小姐约会过
You know,I once dated a Miss Cranky Pants.
可爱的女孩 就是有点情绪化
Lovely girl, kind of moody.
给你 好多了
Here we go, all better.
这才是小乖乖
There's my little boy.
我能试试吗
Can I see something?
酷
Cool!
他讨厌我 我的侄子讨厌我
He hates me! My nephew hates me.
好啦 别这样啦
Come on, don't do this.
要是我自己的孩子恨我 那时我要怎么办啊
What if my own baby hates me? What am I gonna do then?
摩妮卡 别这样 你疯了吗
Monica, would you stop! This is nuts.
你知道还要多久
Do you know how long it's gonna be,
你才会遇到这个问题吗
before you actually have to deal with this problem?
我是说 你连男朋友都还没有
I mean, you don't even have a boyfriend yet.
乔伊 她看起来不胖
Joey, she does not look fat.
【海盗美剧 友情制作】
-== http://www.hdmeiju.com ==-
新浪微博：@海盗美剧
《老友记》蓝光版 第02季 第05集
宝宝落在巴士上了 The One With the Baby on the Bus
调校制作：海盗美剧 寒 枫
字幕编辑：海盗美剧 小龟快快跑
拿去
Here you go.
嘿 摩妮卡
Oh, hey, Mon,
真好笑 借我玩一下
That is so funny! Let me see that a sec.
你没事吧 罗斯      我不知道
You okay, Ross?        I don't know.
派里有什么
What's in this pie?
不知道 黄油 鸡蛋 面粉 青柠檬 奇异果
I don't know. Butter and eggs and flour and lime and kiwi...
奇异果 你说它是个青柠派的
Kiwi? Kiwi? You said it was a key lime pie.
不 我说是奇异果柠檬派
No, I didn't. I said kiwi lime.
所以才特别
That's what makes it so special.
所以才可以害死我
That's what's gonna kill me.
我对奇异果过敏
I'm allergic to kiwi.
不 你过敏的东西是龙虾 花生
No, you're not. You're allergic to lobster and peanuts and...
天啊
Oh my God!
愈来愈严重了
It's definitely getting worse.
你舌头肿起来了吗
All right, is your tongue swelling up?
要不然就是我的嘴变小了
Either that or my mouth is getting smaller!
去穿外套 我们去医院
All right, get your coat. We're gonna go to the hospital.
他会没事吗
Is he gonna be okay?
会的 他只是需要打一针
Yeah, he's just gotta get a shot.
事实上 我已经慢慢好起来了 真的 真的
You know, actually, it's getting better. It is. It is.
我们别去了 谁想玩拼字游戏
Let's not go. Anyone up for Scrabble?
快去穿外套
Jacket, now!
那小本呢 我们不能带个小婴儿去医院
What about Ben? We can't bring a baby to the hospital.
我们可以照顾他
We'll watch him.
不行
I don't think so.
怎么 我有七个天主教姐妹
What? I have seven Catholic sisters.
我照顾过上百个孩子
I've taken care of hundreds of kids.
拜托 我们愿意帮忙 对吧
Come on, we wanna do it, don't we?
我原本想打篮球的
Well, I was looking forward to playing basketball.
但现在球没了 打不成了
But I guess that's out the window.
好吧 你们要是带他出去散步
Ok, well, if you do take him out for his walk,
记得带上他的帽子
just remember bring his hat, okay?
牛奶在冰箱里 尿布在袋子里
And there's extra milk in the fridge, and extra diapers in the bag.
帽子 牛奶 记住了
Hat, milk. Got it!
咱们走      好的
Le's go.         Okay.
包在我们身上
Consider it done!
你听懂了吗
You understood that?
我舅舅萨尔是个大舌头
My uncle Sal has a really big tongue.
是那个 有个漂亮老婆的舅舅吗
Is he the one with the beautiful wife?
嘿 瑞秋
Hey, Rach.
想不想听听 我下午要表演的歌
Wanna hear the new song I'm thingking of singing this afternoon?
我今天早上洗澡时写的      好的
I wrote it this morning in the shower.         Okay.
我在洗澡 我在写一首歌
I'm in the shower and I'm writing a song.
你若已听过 请提醒我
Stop me if you've heard it.
我全身都是泡泡 我的头发已湿透
My skin is soapy and my hair is wet,
秀发倒过来写是发秀
And Tegrin spelled backward is nirget,
瑞秋 你可以过来一下吗
Rachel, sweetheart, could I see you for a minute?
什么事
What's up?
我要告诉你 我决定付钱请专业的歌手
FYI, I've decided to pay a professional musician
每周日下午 来这里唱歌
to play here on Sunday afternoons.
她叫史黛芬妮
Her name is Stephanie something.
应该很出色
She's supposed to be very good.
那菲比呢
But what about Phoebe?
瑞秋 我不是说 你朋友唱得烂
Rachel, it's not that your friend is bad.
事实上是 她非常烂
It's that she's so bad.
以至于我想用手指戳进眼睛
She makes me want to put my finger through my eye
穿透我的脑子 把里面搅成浆糊
into my brain, and swirl it around.
好吧 这么说你不是她的歌迷
Okay, okay, so you're not a fan.
但是 拜托 你不能这样对她
But I mean, come on. You cannot do this to her.
喔 不 不 不
Oh, no, no, no.
得由我来告诉她吗
I have to do this to her?
涂抹 冲水 重复 涂抹 冲水 重复
Lather, rinse, repeat. And lather, rinse, repeat...
视需要而定
As needed.
我觉得 我们东西没带全
You know, I don't think we brought enough stuff.
你是不是忘了带宝宝的铁砧
Did you forget to pack the baby's anvil?
我跟你说 这是值得的
I'm telling you, it's gonna be worth it.
女人都喜欢小宝宝 好吧
It's a known fact that women love babies, all right?
女人喜欢爱小孩的男人
Women love guys who love babies.
这是感性的问题
It's the whole sensitive thing.
快点 把他朝向那边那些美眉
Quick, aim him at that pack of babies over there.
说不定待会儿有一个会过来
Maybe one of them will break away.
等等 别管她们了 这里有一个 左边
Wait, forget them. We got one. Hard left.
宝宝给我      不 我抱就好
All right, give me the baby.         No, I got him.
别这样 我说真的
Come on, seriously.
你是真的想抱他
Oh, seriously, you want him?
你好
Hello.
这个小可爱是谁呀
Who is this little cutie pie?
别认为我不懂得谦虚 你是指 我吗
Well, don't think me immodest, but me?
你想闻闻他吗
You wanna smell him?
我想你指的是宝宝吧
I assume we're talking about the baby now?
喔 是的
Oh, yeah.
他身上有股很棒的宝宝味道 你闻他的头
He's got that great baby smell. Get a whiff of his head.
我想 我的子宫刚刚痉挛了一下
I think my uterus just skipped a beat.
我就说吧
What'd I tell you?
我认为 你们这么做很好
I think it's great you're doing this.
我们是好男人
Well, we are great guys.
我弟弟和他男朋友
You know, my brother and his boyfriend
三年来一直想领养一个孩子
have been trying to adopt for three years.
你们找的是哪个中介机构
What agency did you two go through?
但那是我的节目
But this is my gig.
我一直在这里表演
This is where I play.
我的名字用粉笔写在外面的黑板上
My name is written out there in chalk.
你不能就这样轻易地擦掉粉笔字
You know, you can't just erase chalk.
亲爱的 我很抱歉
Honey, I'm sorry.
而且他还打算付钱给那个女人
And he's going to be paying this woman?
他干嘛不直接送她一个宝座和一个皇冠
Why doesn't he just give her, like a throne and a crown?
再加上 一个上面有颗大球的黄金权仗
And like, you know, a gold stick with a ball on top?
泰利是个混蛋
Terry is a jerk! Okay?
所以我们才一直都骂 "泰利是个混蛋"
That's why we're always saying, "Terry's a jerk!"
那句话就是从这儿来的
That's where that came from.
好吧 你大概已经尽力了
Yeah, okay. You probably did everything you could.
我再看看 还有没有其他办法可想
Okay, you know what? Let me just see what else I can do.
听着
All right, look, look.
你让她在史黛芬妮表演完再之后上场啦
Why don't you just let her go on after Stephanie whatever her name is.
你又不在这里 又不用付她钱
I mean, you won't be here. You don't pay her.
你又不会有什么损失
It's not gonna cost you anything.
我不知道
I don't know.
拜托 泰利 我会帮你清洗卡布奇诺机的
Come on, Terry, I'll even clean the cappuccino machine!
你平常都不清洗卡布奇诺机吗
You don't clean the cappuccino machine?
我当然都有清洗
Of course I clean it.
我是说 我会清洗的
I mean, I will clean it.
我会清洗的
好吧 好啦 好啦 好啦
All right, fine, fine, fine!
成了      真的吗
Done.         Really?
当然  看谁出马嘛 宝贝
Yeah, who's working for you, babe?
老天 太棒了      是啊
Oh my God! This is so exciting!        I know.
我可以拿多少钱
How much am I gonna get?
什么
What?
他说他付钱给在这里表演的人
Well, you said he's paying the people who were playing, so...
不是的 他付钱给那女人
Oh, no, no, no. I meant he's gonna be paying that other woman.
因为她是职业歌手
Because she's a professional.
我才不要当那个唯一没报酬的歌手
I'm not gonna be the only one who's not getting paid.
可是 菲比
But, Pheebs...
很抱歉 我不接受
No, I'm sorry, no!
我才不是什么二流的慈善乐队
No, I'm not some like sloppy second, you know, charity band.
这城里有成千上万个地方
You know what, there are thousands of places in this city,
有人愿意付钱听我唱歌
where people would be happy to pay to hear me play.
我只为我自己弹唱
When I play, I play for me.
我才不需要你的怜悯
I don't need your charity.
谢谢
Thank you!
别想让我打针
There's no way I'm gonna get a shot.
或许他们可以用针筒
Maybe they can take the needle.
把药水往我嘴里喷 就像玩喷水枪
And squirt it into my mouth, y'know, like a squirt gun.
你们好 我是卡林医生      嗨
Hello there. I'm Dr. Carlin.        Hi!
看来 今天有人有一点点过敏反应
I see someone's having a little allergic reaction.
医生 能借一步说话吗
Doctor, can I see you for just a moment, please?
我哥哥有一点针头恐惧症
My brother has a slight phobia about needles.
你有没有告诉他 我的喷水枪的点子
Did you tell him about my squirt gun idea?
我这个博士哥哥想知道
My brother, the PHD., would like to know,
这个药有没有可能用口服的
if there's any way to treat this orally?
不行
No.
在这种情况下 必须要打针
Under these circumstances, it has to be an injection.
而且必须现在就打
And it has to be now.
怎么样
So?
坐下来 医生说必须要打针
That's good, have a seat. The doctor says it's got to be a needle.
你只需要勇敢一点
You're just gonna have to be brave, okay?
就当是为了我 好不好
Can you do that for me?
好吧      好的
Okay         Okay.
很好 你做得非常好
Oh, boy! You are doing so good.
你要捏住我的手吗      要
You wanna squeeze my hand?         Yes.
好吧 罗斯 别捏太紧
Okay! All right, Ross, don't squeeze it so hard.
亲爱的 我说真的 别捏太紧
Honey, really. Don't squeeze it so hard!
噢 罗斯 快放手
Oh Ross, let go of my hand!
真是好点子 乔伊
That's a good plan, Joe.
下次咱们想要泡妞
Next time we want to pick up women,
干脆直接去公园亲热一下就好了
we should just go to the park and make out.
出租车 出租车
Taxi! Taxi!
嘿 瞧那两个辣妹
Hey, hey, look at that talent.
只是在演练 你很不错
Just practicing. You're good.
继续开吧
Carry on.
等等 等等
Wait, wait, wait!
嘿 小宝宝 他好可爱
Hey, you. He's just adorable.
你可以直接告诉他吗
Can you tell him that?
他觉得自己脸色太粉
Because he thinks he looks too pink.
你们今天出来做什么
So, what are you guys out doing today?
我们不是出柜
We're not out.
不是的
No no no.
我们只是两个异性恋男人
We're just two heterosexual guys,
照顾我们另一个异性恋朋友的儿子
hanging with the son of our other heterosexual friend,
做些异性恋做的事
doing the usual straight guy stuff.
你讲完了吗      讲完了
You done?         Yeah.
我们到站了
Oh, there's our stop.
不会吧 我们也在这站下车
Get out of here! This is our stop.
你们也住在这附近吗
You guys live around here too?
是的 当然 我们就住在人行道旁那栋大楼里
Oh, yeah, yeah, sure. We live in the building by the sidewalk.
你们知道吗
You know it?
既然我们是邻居
Hey, look, since we're neighbors and all,
我们去喝一杯 怎么样
what do you say, we get together for a drink?
你们想去麦考餐厅吗
So, you wanna go to Markel's?
当然 他们特别欢迎我们
Oh, sure, they love us over there.
喂 你们的宝宝呢
Hey, where's your baby?
小本 小本
Ben! Ben!
太好了 或许他会听到你喊 拉铃下车
That's good. Maybe he'll hear you and pull the cord!
快停车 喂
Stop the bus! Hey!
车上有个宝宝      等等 等等
Hey, there's a baby!        Wait, wait, wait!
你确定没被他弄断吗 因为真的很痛
Are you sure he didn't break it? Because it really hurts.
没有 只是瘀伤
No, it's just a good bone bruise.
这是 你的戒指造成的刺伤
And right here is the puncture wound from your ring.
对不起 我真的很抱歉      没关系
I'm sorry. I'm really sorry.         It's okay.
对不起
Sorry.
对不起 嘿 我能说清楚话了
Sorry! I got my S's back!
我们晚点再庆祝吧
Which we can celebrate later.
庆祝 庆祝
Celebrate. Celebrate.
他是一个双重 双重 双重关节的男孩
He was a double double double jointed boy.
嘿
Hey.
你就是那个专业的吉他歌手
So, are you the professional guitar player?
是的 我是史黛芬妮
Yeah, I'm Stephanie.
是啊 我的名字原本在上面
Oh, right. My name was on there.
现在被换成胡萝卜蛋糕
But now it just says carrot cake.
好的
Okay.
你会几个和弦
So, how many chords do you know?
都会呀      那么你会D调
All of them.         Oh yeah? So you know D?
会      你会A小调吗
Yeah.         Okay, do you know A minor?
会      好的
Yeah.         Okay.
那你会从D调转A小调吗
Do you know how to go from D to A minor?
会啊      好的
Yeah.         Okay.
那你的吉它有背带吗
So does your guitar have a strap?
没有      我的有
No.         Oh. Mine does.
史黛芬妮知道所有和弦
Stephanie knows all the chords.
拜托 接电话 快接 快接呀
Come on! Pick up! pick up! pick up!
喂
Hello.
运输管理局吗  你好
Transit Authority? Yes, hello!
我正在为一本书做研究
I'm doing research for a book.
我想知道 如果有人把宝宝
I was wondering what somebody might do
遗留在巴士上 应该怎么办
if they left a baby on a city bus.
是的 我知道 只有笨蛋才会这么做
Yes, I do realize that would be a stupid character.
你好 是这样的
Hi! Here's the deal.
我们今天遗留了一个儿童座椅在巴士上
We lost a car seat on a bus today.
白塑胶材质 有把手 能放进推车里
It's white plastic, with a handle, and it fits onto a stroller.
对了 里面还有一个宝宝
Oh, and there was a baby in it.
他想和你说
He wants to talk to you.
各位 我们以最热烈的掌声欢迎
Okay, everybody, let's give a nice warm Central Perk welcome to...
泰利是个混蛋 他不让我工作
Terry's a jerk and he won't let me work.
我痛恨中央咖啡厅
And I hate Central Perk.
欢迎 史黛芬妮希佛
to Stephanie Schiffer!
首先我想唱一首 我为我的初恋情人写的歌
I'll just start with a song that I wrote for the first man I ever loved.
查克端
Zachary...
都去死吧
Are all invited to bite me.
我们刚才打电话来询问宝宝的事 他在这里吗
We're the guys that called about the baby! Is he here?
他在这里
He's here.
我猜 你们其中一个是宝宝的父亲
I assume one of you is the father.
就是我      是我
That's me.         I'm him.
事实上 我们俩都是孩子的父亲
Actually, we're both the father.
喔 小本      嘿 小鬼
Oh Ben!        Hey, buddy.
请告诉我 你知道 哪个是我们的宝宝
Please tell me you know which one is our baby.
那个衣服上有鸭子 这个上面是小丑
That one has ducks on his T shirt and this one has clowns.
小本的衣服上的图案绝对是鸭子
And Ben was definitely wearing ducks.
或小丑
Or clowns.
等等
Oh, oh, wait.
那个绝对是小本
That one's definitely Ben!
记得他嘴巴旁有颗可爱的小痣
Remember he had that cute little mole by his mouth!
是吗      是的
Yeah?         Yeah.
嘿 小本 记得我们吗
Hey, Ben! Remember us?
痣掉下去了
Okay, the mole came off.
我们该怎么办 我们该怎么办
What are we gonna do? What are we gonna do?
我们抛硬币决定 鸭子或小丑
We'll flip for it. Ducks or clowns.
抛硬币决定
Oh, we're gonna flip for the baby?
你有更好的点子
You got a better idea?
好吧 丢上去就喊
All right, call it in the air.
正面
Heads.
正面      万岁
Heads, it is.         Yes.
我们得先决定正面代表什么
We have to assign heads to something!
对 好的
Right! Okay.
好的
Okay.
鸭子代表正面 因为鸭子有头
Ducks is heads because ducks have heads.
给你庆祝生日的小丑没有头 不会吓坏你吗
What kind of scary ass clowns came to your birthday?
叫我清晨的天使
Just call me angel of the morning, angel.
在离开我之前 轻触我的脸颊  宝贝
Just touch my cheek Before you leave me, baby.
叫我清晨的天使
Just call me angel of the morning, angel.
然后慢慢转身离去
Then slowly turn away.
我不会求你留下来 陪我
I won't beg you to stay with me.
嘿      嗨
Hey         Oh. hi.
来 我想你一定冷了
Here. I thought you might be cold.
谢谢
Thank you.
瞧瞧你 收获不少呢
Oh, look at you. You did pretty well.
八块二毛七
Eight dollars and twenty seven cents.
不完全是 因为我一开始放了两块钱
But not really, because I put in the first two.
一点彩头 同时也让我自己好过些
Just to, you know, get the ball rolling and to make myself feel better.
你有好过些吗
Do you?
没有
No.
卖唱这码子事 实在不适合我
You know, this whole like playing-for-money thing is so not good for me.
我唱"我要自杀"那首歌时
You know, I don't know, when I sang "Su su suicide"
赚到一块七毛五
I got a dollar seventy five.
可是"臭猫"呢
But then "Smelly Cat"? Oh.
我只赚到两毛五和一个安全套
I got 25 cents and a condom.
所以 我替"臭猫"觉得很难过
So, you know, now I just feel really bad for "Smelly Cat".
你知道
Well, you know.
亲爱的 我认为不是每个人都听得懂"臭猫"
Honey, I don't think everybody gets "Smelly Cat", you know?
如果他们只养过健康的宠物 八成完全听不懂
I mean, if all you've ever actually had are healthy pets, then whoosh!
不光只是那样
But it's not even that, you know?
以前我唱我写的歌 是因为那让我很开心
It's just, I used to do my songs because it made me happy.
现在却变成 完全是为了钱
Now it's like, it's just all about the money, you know?
店里有人想念你
Well, people missed you in there.
事实上 有人点唱"臭猫"
And in fact, there was actually a request for "Smelly Cat."
真的吗 谁
Really? From who?
我
Well, me.
我知道那不是你最卖座的歌
And I know it's not your, y'know, big money song.
但那是我的最爱
But it's my favorite.
嗨
Hi.
我刚才是否不小心 掉了一个安全套在箱子里
Did I accidentally drop a condom in your case?
情况紧急
It's kind of an emergency.
是的
Yeah.
拿去吧      多谢
Here you go.         Hey, thanks a lot.
克莉丝汀 我拿到了
Hey, Christine! I got it!
谢谢你 今天一直陪着我
I just wanna thank you for being there for me today.
很抱歉 我差点捏断你的手
And I'm sorry I almost broke your hand.
没关系 很抱歉 我害你中毒
That's okay. I'm sorry I poisoned you.
还记不记得 我以前用铅笔刺你的手
Hey, remember the time I jammed that pencil into your hand?
记不记得 你认为这是什么 雀斑吗
Remember it? What do you think this is, a freckle?
记得我曾经 用西尔维亚的南瓜 往你脸上扔
What about the time I hit you in the face with Sylvian's pumpkin?
你记得我把扫帚 插进你的脚踏车轮里
Remember when I stuck that broom in your bike spokes,
害你翻倒 头撞到路边那次吗
and you flipped over and hit your head on the curb?
不记得
No.
不过我记得大家老是告诉我那件事
But I remember people telling me about it.
真希望小本有个妹妹
I hope Ben has a little sister.
是啊
Yeah.
我希望她能好好管教他
And I hope she can kick his ass.
我去换个新的创可贴
I'm gonna get a new Band Aid.
记得我曾经 把你的马利布肯娃娃脚剪掉吗
How about the time I cut the legs off your Malibu Ken?
原来是你
That was you?
他的脚感染了 不剪掉不行
They were infected. He wouldn't have made it.
噢
Oh!
我的小侄子
My little nephew.
过来 小宝贝
Come here, little one!
我的小宝贝 小本
Oh. There's my little baby, Ben!
我的小乖乖
Hey, my little boy. Oh.
他没哭耶
Hey, he's not crying!
万岁
Yes.
还有派
There's still pie!
我来了 我来了
I'm here. I'm here.
我的小宝贝好吗
How's my little boy, huh?
你要爸爸替你换尿布吗 我知道
You want Daddy to change your diaper? I know. I know.
你今天和乔伊叔叔 钱德叔叔玩得开心吗
So, did you have fun with Uncle Joey and Uncle Chandler today?
当然啦
Oh, yeah.
他今天还坐巴士了呢
He rode the bus today.
大男孩坐巴士
Big boy riding the bus...
我有个问题
Hey, I have a question.
为什么他的屁股上面写着 "公共事业财产"
How come it says "Property of Human Services" on his butt?
你 你一定会喜欢这故事的
You, you are gonna love this.
你可以抱一下小本吗
Can you hold Ben for a sec?
过来 过来
Come here. Come here.
退后 我手上有奇异果 快跑 乔伊 快跑
Stay back! I've got kiwi! Run, Joey, run!
臭猫 臭猫
Smelly cat, smelly cat
他们喂你吃了什么
What are they feeding you?
不 很抱歉 应该是
No, no. I'm sorry,it's...
臭猫 臭猫
Smelly cat, smelly cat...
好多了      是吗
Better!        Yeah?
好多了 很好
Much better. Good.
别难过 因为这首歌挺难的
Don't feel bad, because it's a hard song.
是啊
Yeah.
要再来一次吗      从头
You want to try it again?         Yeah, from the top?
没有"从头" 好吧
Okay, there is no "top", all right?
那便是"臭猫"的美妙之处
That's the beauty of "Smelly Cat".
你跟我唱好了
Why don't you just follow me?
好吧
Okay.
臭猫 臭猫
Smelly cat, smelly cat,
他们喂你吃了什么
What are they feeding you?
臭猫 臭猫
Smelly cat, smelly cat,
这不是你的错
It's not your fault.
那太多了 抱歉
That's too much. Sorry.
【海盗美剧 友情制作】
-== http://www.hdmeiju.com ==-
新浪微博：@海盗美剧